<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bradley T. Rentz</title>
    <link>https://rentzb.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bradley T. Rentz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Bradley T. Rentz</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rentzb.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Correspondence Analysis</title>
      <link>https://rentzb.github.io/post/ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 21:13:14 -1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rentzb.github.io/post/ca/</guid>
      <description>What to do with categorical data?  Categorical data can be challenging to analyze quantitatively In language research we often have data that are purely categorical In today’s presentation we will deal with a specific type of categorical data found in questionnaires   Questionnaire Data  Questionnaires are frequently used in a variety of language research scenarios They often ask people to rate something (likert scales) or select the most appropriate response There are often multiple questions that have the same answer scale (same choices) Example: select the language that is most appropriate to use in a given domain Example: rate level of agreement with several statements   Research Question  Often we are interested in how the questions relate to each other in terms of their answers as well as how the answers relate to each other based on the questions they were most used with   Correspondence Analysis  CA is statistical technique that shows how the questions and answers of multiple questions relate to each other Requires the data to have the same scale (all questions must have some possible answers) CA is a descriptive tool and doesn’t give p-values per se   How does CA work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://rentzb.github.io/post/r_markdown_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rentzb.github.io/post/r_markdown_intro/</guid>
      <description>This document comes from a UH-Mānoa data science group for linguists presentation
This is a top level section R Markdown This is an R Markdown presentation. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
When you click the Knit button a document will be generated that includes both content as well as the output of any embedded R code chunks within the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Bayesian Linear Mixed Effect Models with rstanarm</title>
      <link>https://rentzb.github.io/post/intro_bayesian_pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rentzb.github.io/post/intro_bayesian_pdf/</guid>
      <description>Overview of Presentation  Bayesian vs. frequentist inference Bayes’ Theorem Example of Bayesian inference Bayesian LMERs with rstanarm how to code models selecting priors displaying &amp;amp; interpreting the posterior distribution model diagnostics and comparisons   Bayesian vs. Frequentist Inference Frequentist Inference  Uses only the data and compares it to an idealized model to make inferences about the data Example Problem: You lose your cellphone in your house. You have a friend call it and you listen for the sound to find it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Git</title>
      <link>https://rentzb.github.io/post/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rentzb.github.io/post/git/</guid>
      <description>What is Git? Git is…  A distributed version control system Used to allow multiple people to collaborate on the same code Also useful for managing your own code and larger projects   Applications for language researchers?  Coauthoring papers Working on R scripts or other code Sharing code with others (via github or bitbucket) Managing large projects like a dissertation, thesis, or article   What does Git do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Data</title>
      <link>https://rentzb.github.io/post/tidy_data_handout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rentzb.github.io/post/tidy_data_handout/</guid>
      <description>What is tidy data? Tidy data have the following characteristics:
 Observations are in rows Variables are in columns Contained in a single dataset  An example of tidy data   Participant Gender Trial Value    01 M 1 100  01 M 2 210  02 F 1 50  02 F 2 75     An example of messy data   Participant Trial1 Trial2    M01 100 210  F02 50 75     R Packages for tidy data library(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;) ## ── Attaching packages ─────────────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>